hello I'm your host David Bernard and
with me today Revenue cat CEO Jacob
piding Our Guest today is Ryan Beck
co-founder and CTO pray.com an app with
the mission to grow Faith cultivate
community and leave a legacy of helping
others on the podcast we talk with Ryan
about the risk of AD creative
concentration how to reach older high
value
demographics and why the ultimate kpi is
still just Revenue hey Ryan thanks so
much for joining us on the podcast today
yeah well thank you very much David
Jacob for having me I look forward to
the conversation and Jacob always nice
to chat with you this nice Monday
morning this beautiful day for
podcasting dud let's go so Ryan I wanted
to dig in first to the story of pray.com
we don't always go into the story but I
think we've got some like interesting
twists and turns along the way that I
think the audience would be interested
in hearing so so tell us about the
founding of pray.com and kind of those
early years the original thesis was we
saw the need in the faith space for
digitization traditionally Faith space
has been laggards in technology adoption
so they've been hesitant to go on social
and things like this and we saw that
coming to kind of an end where reality
was going to meet dogma and reality was
going to win out what I mean by that is
churches have been operating Faith
organizations have been operating a
certain way for Millennia quite
literally and so coming in and and doing
a Netflix to their Blockbuster
was something they resisted and that was
not something we wanted to do we wanted
to help them transition and so that was
the whole thing so we started off with a
private social network for Faith
organizations and so we had some of the
largest Faith organizations across the
country on the platform and that went
really well we had great retention you
know Facebook level retention The Social
Network was going great in order to on
board these Faith organizations you had
to go to them and you generally had to
go to them more than once to get to a %
penetration rate of on boarding their
organization and the problem is Faith
organizations they're open generally one
day a week where everyone's there and
it's usually the same day and so the
Salesforce needed for that and I also
Imagine the uh folks you could recruit
to sell this product probably are busy
on that day I would guess that is true
yeah you need a sales professional that
has the faith background yeah just an
army of atheists selling your product
probably not going to connect no they
they probably would not they would not
and so yeah that was uh that was how we
started and then one of the things you
told me while we were kind of prepping
for this is that you also were worked
multi or not even multi-denominational
but across all faiths right so it was
like Buddhists and Muslims and
Christians and kind of like worked
across all Fai I imagine that was a
challenge as well in those early days it
was interesting to work with some of the
largest Moss synagogues temples parishes
and churches because we saw ourselves as
this rather basic platform form in which
Faith organizations could build the pawn
and so we didn't want in really any
nonprofit We didn't want to be pigeon
hold into one we wanted to build a
platform that was rather to use a term
agnostic to religion coming on because
we saw this space was underserved and so
we actually didn't have a lot of
resistance now all the founders were all
Christian Founders and so we had to come
at it with a little bit of humility and
uh as we you know approach some of these
religions that were not ours and explain
to them the heart and the thesis around
it because they all have the same
problem no matter their religion and
they all have the same goal just they
look at it from a different different
lens right they're just trying to help
their Community generally speaking and
they're trying to promote virtues and
values in that Community with their
people you launched a product you had
like amazing retention the main problem
you talked about was kind of needing
this Salesforce but what else wasn't
working if you had such amazing
retention and then you know where did
you go from there these organizations
they tend to be a little bit older on
the demographic scale and so virality
isn't um isn't something that you're
going to get with with that type of
demographic like you would with maybe
the high school demographic or college
demographic where they're sharing their
digital natives when we're going to
these organizations we have a booth in
which they're coming to us to ask us how
do you download an app right and you all
were mobile first we were mobile first
we were mobile first because we thought
the in rightfully so that's just where
even they were even at that time and you
can fast forward now post pandemic our
parents are probably texting us where
they used to just call us right they're
and now they're texting us you're like
thank God they're they're actually
texting us now and not just calling us
all the time you know but yeah I can
imagine even even in the past five years
or so there's still transition happening
especially in those like older cohorts
in terms of like behaviors and there's
probably some cohorts that just will
never make the mobile transition even
for like a given computer savviness I
feel like mobile is still easier because
of what you described there at least
they can bring you their computer to the
booth meaning their phone you know what
I mean like you can't help somebody
who's like at a a Dell at home that
you're trying to figure out how to log
in but still it's got have a lot of
challenges you know before we move on to
to kind of what you did next I do think
it's interesting because this older
demographic while I mean especially
since 2020 has kind of adopted
technology a little more than they did
in the past especially on mobile but it
is still like a high paying demographic
I mean you know I've talked to a lot of
apps where younger cohorts don't perform
well even my own like weather app like I
look at Stats and like the payers are
like men over 45 and I think there's
probably going to be a lot of apps where
the boomer generation with trillions of
wealth I spend it on something it might
as well be apps you know what I mean how
about that any lessons from that time
period about like kind of working with
those demographics and those cohorts we
may get into it a little bit more and
this ties into you know when we started
doing Performance Marketing and focus
more on consumer subscription we went TV
worked really well for us pre pandemic
and and during the pandemic because that
older cohort was there and that was the
medium in which they trusted for
advertisement digital was not something
they necessarily trusted as widely now
Facebook was and still is to some extent
in Facebook proper right is still King
of that demographic and it does a very
good job of that but the TV platform
worked really well when that audience
was there and so we were able to kind of
meet that demographic where they were at
on their technology Journey a lot of
them were still on TV and radio at that
time and now they're starting to get
more and more digital native and in
generally it's mobile and so yes that
demographic it pays higher the higher
ltvs there's a little more difficulty in
getting them to conversion though and so
you know it can balance out for us it
worked out better that demographic
generally is I higher LTV they align
more and just if you think about our own
life Journeys we start thinking about
faith and religion generally later on in
life when families come into play and
you're thinking about how do I raise my
kid where do I settle down you're
starting to think about those things
that religion generally talks about
those value based kind of foundations
that you want maybe to instill your kids
they may not be religion but for a lot
of people jumping ahead right because at
some point Y all decided to not focus on
uh like a social network aspect anymore
right like what led up into that
decision like what were the inputs that
that made yall decide like okay we need
a different a different tack is really
the growth so retention was great but
you know when we modeled out the growth
it wasn't fast enough and we're a
venture capital backed company and so
you know speed is uh velocity is very
important to us and so we we were always
looking for ways in which we can speed
up our growth rate and so we started
doing the from our social network we
found these daily prayers were very
helpful these pastors would send out
messages to Their audience text messages
to to Their audience and people would
resonate with them was this an emergent
behavior that that was happening on your
network or was this something you all
built into like a feature like daily
notifications or it was both so it was
emergent in that we these were just
normal social posts that you would see
on a Facebook group so it wasn't like a
daily prayer feature but it was
something that people were were doing
yeah but we tied in text messages that
was kind of the thing because people
really wanted to gravitate towards these
and so we we found that they were
operating a little bit different than
social posts and that people really
engaged with these what we found was
there's an analog to this in the
physical world in which they're kind of
these little quote cards but they're
Faith quotes and that's basically what
these pastors were giving and what we
added on the capability they could
record an audio or a video clip and so
what you are finding is they do these
social posts with a little bit of a
devotional behind the quote and so
that's what's led to our daily our
morning noon and nightly prayers which
is kind of a a main feature of our app
if you you go and you see it you'll see
and that's what transitioned us into
this content where we're like well we
can make these
devotionals and we created those
devotionals in 2019 they worked really
well had great engagement and then
that's what led us into our entry into
subscription because we started doing
more long form are you still maintaining
the the social product is it still part
of it yes and it's tucked away because
there are some people that still use it
and it's going to be revitalized here in
some fashion but it will not look the
same as like a Facebook group most
likely but it's tucked away you it's
hard to get to yeah it's tough when you
when you have you have products that are
like used but maybe don't fit your
business need and like how to
responsibly like pivot away and like you
know take careful stakeholders and
everything especially when they're
stakeholders you care about in the sense
of like their perception of your brand
and whatnot right they're still
potential future customers so it's
really interesting that I thought you
were going to say digital analog of
prayer chains is this a thing this is a
thing I'm me in rural Ohio we used to
have like a phone chain that you know
you sometimes they used to have this for
school before like one to many
communication right the school was
something was going on you'd have you
call this person then you call the next
person but that was like all the
parishes around here would have like
prayer chains like we needed to hit the
phones if there's something going on I
thought that's what it was going to be
about but I imagine people probably use
it for that that kind of thing too yeah
we built a feature that you were able to
build These Chains it was kind of like
we we took from Twitter and our ex now
that kind of you can add these these
threads onto your post that had context
and you could say oh yes it was answered
or hey we're still need you know here's
an update so people can update it they
can answer it so yeah there's a lot of
analog in the physical world that we're
able to just pretty seamlessly
transition to the digital world that's
why we started with like hey there's a
lot of practices that we do physically
that can go into the digital world very
seamlessly you just got to get people
over to that digital world let's keep
talking through this pivot of the app
but through the lens of monetization so
were you monetizing the app before this
transition to subscriptions like did you
have ads in the app or was it zero
monetization and you're like okay we
have something here and we're going to
transition to subscription to actually
monetize it or were we already
monetizing we were mon in through
donations we weren't monetizing the
organizations on our platform were
monetizing and we had you were
facilitating donations right yeah we
were facilitating them and so there was
some transaction volume and it was
significant it was in the million so it
was it was good and it was in 2019 when
we added the revenue the monetization on
our side where we started collecting a
subscription fee so how did you
determine in those early days I mean it
sounds like this key feature these like
daily prayer things were the kind of
Main monetizable feature what was that
like process of deciding what to
monetize what did you monetize and how
did things go you know for us there's
clear paths some of the giant CSS
companies of the prepandemic era of like
the comms and headspace they had gone
down that path it was more secular right
so they had Comm had figured out sleep
content and so for us there was a lot of
similarities that we could do but more
on the faith perspective rather than the
secular perspective and so we just
tested out you know we saw what was
working for other people I'm a big fan
of imitate iterate and innovate and I
would rather imitate to start because
Innovation is hard right you don't know
how it's going to perform and how it
goes live but imitation you can set
benchmarks and so we were able to roll
out bedtime Bible stores sleep Psalms
and some of these contents that were
people were Finding Traction to already
and then meditative prayers and things
like that that had an analoges to what
people were already consuming in the
secular space so that that made it easy
and we just it ated I mean it was
constant test we redid our whole product
platform to allow for testing of
onboarding flows paywalls having that
from the server side so that we didn't
have to deploy new apps every time we
wanted to test something and so we were
able to run rapid iterations on our
tests and that's really what helped us
figure out that what could monetize and
what couldn't monetize and then how far
we could take that monetization I think
a lot of apps especially apps that are
free are very nervous to monetize and
then those that are already monetizing
are nervous to mess with the
monetization of like putting different
features behind pay walls adding new
features that are paid versus free don't
want to kill the Golden Goose that was
like driving the retention you were
talking about like Facebook like
retention any kind of lessons from some
of those early iterations on like how
the the community responded to
monetization you know how you introduced
it and how you ated on that to get to
where you are today it was you know
being very data driven so you know
there's data informed and uh that seems
to be the Pinnacle I'm I'm very much a
student of data driven product
development so looking at the data
seeing how people are responding and
that data is sometimes quantitative and
sometimes qualitative so customer
feedback you're looking at how many
reports you're getting on certain things
and you're listening to your customers
and you're listening to the data you're
listening to the customers through the
data their interaction
and so we let that be the guide and we
set up kpis right so you have average
revenue per user uh there retention and
these are things that are tradeoffs
right you can model these out you can
figure out if I have my retention is X
and it goes down by 10% what is that due
to my longtail Revenue right you can
model these things out and so you just
have to have a robust understanding of
the data and how the kpis you want to
look at in a consumer impact that
revenue and ultim Ely you want to be do
what's best for the customer because
that's how you're going to monetize but
then you have to make sure that you can
sustain a business we for-profit
business right yeah I was going to say I
think uh taking on venture capital is a
good way to not worry about charging for
things you know what I mean David I
think this this usually the Indie
developers who feel like there's no need
for a return and all of this is you know
free that's like oh I can't charge but
you know when you got a but did you see
any specific or do you have any specific
examples that come to mind of
qualitative push back of like oh they
shouldn't because I think I forget if it
was prey.com or some other religious
based app I had talked to or or looked
at at some point that got push back that
like this is Faith it's Church it should
be free like it's you know greed is is
bad and like monetization is evil like
was there qualitative feedback on that
kind of stuff as you did start to push
toward monetization there's some you can
you know that's probably all of our
negative reviews is you get big enough
there you can find a hater for every
topic right and it's not for everybody
and we respect that that's why we have a
free version that people can enjoy and
they don't have to pay and so it's a
balance when you're running a business
between making sure that the customers
because the customer is who you're
building for the value you're trying to
deliver you want to listen to them and
there is going to be a segment of those
especially probably more so in the faith
space that expect things to be free
because that's kind of how the model has
worked previously and and so it's a
balance and yes we do get it and we you
know we try to we respond to every
customer feedback anytime someone writes
in we respond we'll get feedback that
says doubt anybody's going to respond to
this and just charging trying to make
money and we'll respond and how get on a
call my business partner Steve who's the
CEO he'll get on a call and then we have
a great customer support person who runs
that ear who there is not
one report that comes in positive or
negative that is not getting a person
responding and so that's how we've
handled it and it's labor intensive but
that was something we decided from the
very beginning and that's how we've
handled the objections uh to make sure
that we hear them and we respect them
because they do come in and more so in
the faith space I mean it's a lot of
these things are a fine line even
outside of the face space like you just
got to use your judgment I think people
and just in general people over rotate
on negative comments more than they they
do on positive and I think that's what
throws a lot of Developers for a loop
there was a crazy Reddit through I got
find it this weekend about developer who
got one his first negative review for
charging money and was like ready to
like take down the pay wall and
everything I I just like no no no it's
fine this is it's working as expected
it's working as expected if nobody
complains about your price you're not
charging enough so people are
complaining about having to pay you're
doing the right thing because it's a
signal that they want it so like you're
building something valuable it's like a
positive signal of value creation yeah
nobody complains about products they
don't care about right that's also a
truth and nobody complains about a price
of something that they don't want like
if trash is sitting on the ground you're
not complaining that it cost something
like they actually want it which is a
good signal but that's what that mean
you go back to data driven right that's
what indicators like retention
indicators like conversion rate
indicators like LTV RPO you can just
like turn the dials and if you can see
what the Alchemy does right like what
the other numbers go up and down and you
can kind of understand I think it's just
really hard to not really hard
but I do think it takes some wisdom and
and sort of like a steady hand to be
able to also integrate that qualitative
feedback you know what I mean there like
individuals right it's easy to look at a
conversion rate and say like oh well you
know 80% of the people didn't buy it's
harder to like talk to one of those 80%
of people who thinks you're like ripping
them off you know what I mean so being
able to handle both of those is is
tricky but it's important especially in
consumer where you have to really
synthesize like qualitative and
quantitative yeah there's lots of data
lots of input and speaking of that to
synthesize but I'll ask a question any
top lessons from that time of a win or a
fail so like one kind of like test you
did on the monetization that was just
like doubled revenue or something crazy
like that and then on the contrary any
like change you tried to make like
massively impacted retention in a way
you're like revert revert revert any any
of those kind of wins or fails that you
can think of that you want to share I
mean there's a few and there's some that
early on in The Social Network it was
phone email name right you're going into
these communities we want to make sure
you're a real person and we had the
phone in there and consumer subscription
we do now we found ways to work with it
but that phone number was not working
with consumer subscription and it was
tough to get it back in there you mean
requesting the phone number would cause
such high drop off in it cause such high
turn that you couldn't then monetize so
by removing the requirement of a phone
you would then better correct correct so
you you know that onboarding experience
just like when you're onboarding new
employees to your company or into your
product that customer onboarding is the
most important part of the customer
journey and so really really honing in
that placement of the pay wall making
sure that it you know you could put it
up front you can put it as the first
thing and you may get some that initial
conversion may go up but then that
longtail that LTV and so you just have
to understand those further down those
longtail metrics and so I think another
thing when we were running lots and lots
of paid advertisements some of the
failings in paid advertisement is not
having a diversity of creative so we had
meta going it was tens of thousands of
dollars a day and most of it was behind
one creative it was performing really
great and it had five stars in the
description
and meta approved it they said looks
good but then meta decided you know what
not good and they took it down on a dime
and it totally went upside down our our
CS went upside down our customer
acquisition costs were untable and so we
had to bring down those campaigns retool
it figure it out and then bring them
back up and this was part of that Q5 you
know of post Christmas to end of January
when everything is really great for CSS
companies yeah consumer subscription
holidays you know like yeah so you mean
like diversity just like having more
creative content on Advertising than you
need right yeah so just like if you're
an investor and you have an Investment
Portfolio you don't want 80% of your
Investments tied up in one creative you
want it to be maybe if it's an Nvidia
you got 30% Max right but if you do
anything more than that you you run a
little bit of a risk and so you want to
your creative diversification is is very
important and so that's was something
that was a that was a hard lesson
learned because it costs lots of money
how do you do creative do you have that
all inous or do you work with agencies
or what's your process we've done both
now we work with a great a agency they
run it and we've developed kind of a
Playbook prior to working with them that
we we like to run and so we are probably
one of their most aggressive uh clients
when it comes to creative testing they
work with some really big names some of
the names that are part of the that GP
bullhound chart right right so we just
run a very aggressive creative testing
there's really nothing that within
limits obviously there's concerns but
there we'll try pretty much anything we
look across Industries we aren't looking
at oh how does uh media companies we're
looking at gaming we're looking at
dating all these different apps How what
are they running to find that
inspiration because of going back to
that kind of the the triple ey framework
that imitate iterate innovate and so
we're running our we're doing
diversification across that that
generally leads us to a well Diversified
creative mix that's helping us scale our
campaigns I'm sure there's interesting
um inside the the Facebook's black box
of optimization I'm sure there's really
interesting emerging phenomenon when
you're trying to Traverse like a
demographic that's usually unstated or
like Facebook doesn't have a necessarily
know but they probably kind of do know
you know what I mean because they should
probably Target based on but they also
need to you know known Christians or
known people who would resonate with
your content but then they also to grow
The Tam they probably should be
it might be the case that the Facebook
algorithm is the greatest evangelist in
the world in terms of like net net
evangelism you know what I mean do you
think about that do you consider
yourself to selling to folks who are
already within the faith and like
strengthening their faith or or do you
think about like expanding Beyond you
know maybe folks who aren't like
actively involved in the faith I
wouldn't speak for meta to you know
determine if they're the greatest
evangelist but their algorithm is very
good it's still the best in the market
for applications mobile applications and
the way we approach that is that we kind
of let meta do its thing and they're
pretty good and we find a breath right
from people who are curious to people
who are strong in you know going to
their Faith organization on a weekly
basis uh so it's the whole gamut and
Facebook figures it out yeah I'm sure
how do you um think about those
different customer profiles on like like
content side and like product side do
you do you think about like folks who
are maybe I mean there's probably many
dimensions that you can cut up that
content on right depending on
denominations or not and things like
this I I imagine that's kind of a an
interesting puzzle as well I think that
pre idfa there's a little more more
controls that were helpful I personally
haven't seen post idfa where those
controls have been a net benefit over
time maybe in to make sure I understood
your question how I how I'm interpreting
is sometimes you can get fine grained
with your audience matching
and I find that pre ID F there it was a
little bit better I'm wondering just
like from a you know you get somebody in
net from wherever right like how do you
think about what kind of content is
within the app you know depending on
those different profiles of like you
know the Curious all the way to the like
super strong in their faith and then and
then across also like the different
denominations and and and styles of of
things it's got to be an interesting
problem to determine like where you
focus your investment right yeah like I
mean on on boarding are you ask asking
people like you know do you attend
regularly and then do you show different
content and different experiences based
on some of that kind of data the
questions that you ask one of the
strategies that have has worked well is
some sort of light or heavy kind of quiz
funnel in your onboarding to help
understand what's that weight loss at
that really put you no that put you
through the ringer you know it's like a
multi-day onboarding event you know and
got book it you got to get it on your
calendar take some PTO yeah they really
you know showcased how you can you can
utilize these quizzes to optimize the
user experience post onboarding to make
it feel more for them and I would say
we're light in our journey there but
there's things that we do to make sure
that we're we're helping guide them in
their in their faith Journey because all
these things all these indicators right
they could be used for kind of Nefarious
or malicious purposes but you can also
use these things to help people in their
healthy habits and that's where we focus
on is helping people with healthy habits
just like n right they want to take in
that information so that they can help
you in your weight loss journey and help
you become healthier people won't pay
you for reinforcing bad habits I mean
they will but like not forever right you
want those long-term customers that's
where the money is so we really focus on
developing those getting those questions
answered in onboarding to help us
facilitate that mental and spiritual
health track that they want to go on
we've been talking about meta are you
experimenting with Tik Tok and snap and
all sorts of other even tabula those
kind of ads seem to maybe perform well
for your demographic yeah any other kind
of channels that you're experimenting
with or seeing success with we
experiment with most of the channels but
we always come back to kind of meta I
think post idfa for mobile applications
they're the ones that seem to be ahead
of the curve as as far as figuring it
out and how to handle this app tracking
and deliver the right ads to the right
people so that people on their platform
can resonate with it and find Value in
that product and so they they seem to be
ahead of the curve and we're on our you
know Google platforms and and Tik Tok
and things like that but we find that
the consistency is with the meta
platform that's just where they have a
wide array of products that you can
Market on and advertise on and and reach
a wide demographic to help them in their
faith Journey better than some of the
other other platforms do you find within
meta do you focus on like more instag
because I like Facebook itself has reals
within it as well and I don't know if
they like actually separate the two
anymore do you have a sense of like
which specific apps in their platform
are resonating the best or is it kind of
all over the place yeah I would say that
early on it used to be mostly Facebook
we would talk to the meta rep and early
on pre idfa like call it 2020 2019 that
we would run a lot of images and it
would be on Facebook they would resonate
really well like in Fe ads basically
yeah and they were like now everyone's
moving a video and like man these videos
there're a lot more to to make but it's
say 100 times the cost of production
right yeah but they weren't really
resonating and maybe it was on us in its
transition Now video is kind of more the
dominant form yeah they've also raised
the prevalence of video and short short
form video in every app I complain about
this every app has reels now like every
app like Gmail's going to have reals
soon like but I guess it's also helpful
because you probably have one you know
focus on short form video creative and
then you can deploy that across a bunch
of different platforms yeah and when
when Tik Tok kind of became a mstay
application I'm a big fan of meta's
quarterly earnings so we'll we're
listening to those and probably
providing a lot of them and so I was
just like hey we need to um we started
investing in the reels early on and and
now that's where it predominantly is and
it spread across the the application
verse for meta and I wouldn't say
Facebook is you know by far the the
leader anymore and I think that it's
been 5 years is you know four or five
years and you're getting new people and
we had a a kind of an accelerated Tech
adoption cycle with the pandemic that
moved people across platforms and made
people more comfortable our parents are
now scanning QR codes they weren't doing
that and so they you know they became
mobile capable now and so you're seeing
different demographic shift across these
applications earlier you mentioned TV
and radio I wanted to dig in that a
little bit and one of the things you
said and maybe we can talk about these
things in parallel but I'd never thought
about trust before in ads and the way
you said it was that you know that older
generation trusts tv ads like if it's on
TV it's true kind of mentality which is
unfortunately led many astray I think
how does trust play into that and like
creating ads on platforms that people
trust and in ways that people trust but
then what does the TV strategy look like
now with maybe that's not as big of a
deal for folks as seen on TV is a real
thing right as seen on Instagram is not
a real thing and so that trust element
is there with TV you may have an
influence on Instagram and YouTube that
you're like oh Mr Beast promotes this or
so and so um I have no idea what Mr
Beast promotes but he is the first
influencer that came on my mind and so I
think what you find is the influencer
has the weight of the medium before it
so TV was the medium and that had a lot
of weight so if people saw it they
thought this is legit why because the
barrier to entry was higher five bucks
gets me on Instagram my advertisement
right five bucks does not get me on TV
and so you know that's one of the things
that you you find your your strategy is
a lot different it's more akin to
betting rather than Investments where I
feel like digital Performance Marketing
on digital is more to investment
strategy it's like betting but you also
don't know if you won until your tax
season next year right cuz like but like
how do you find out like you bet on a
big ad on CNN or something like this do
you even try to like do some attribution
there do you find it useful or do you
just go like we know this kind of has to
kind of work oh no we we are in the data
data driven to the core I mean we are
looking at by minute we're looking at
realtime feeds when we run it we have a
great brand with prey.com that resonates
very well this is technical question but
like who you work with like a platform
for TV ad buys and they actually give
you by the minute when ads are running
yes and they would help us with that
media mix modeling but it would just be
for broadcast and then we'd have our
Performance Marketing so you have to
blend it so from the very beginning
we've been doing media mix modeling and
so we've been comfortable kind of flying
with statistical models rather than you
know very deterministic models of
Performance Marketing which is I think
is the evolution of versus maybe five or
six years ago I think with the at made
this more important it's just like there
always was uncertainty I just think
people didn't want to admit there was
now we just accept that there's
uncertainty right and you just roll with
it it's really interesting I see I
anecdotally like when I'm sitting at my
parents house and they've got Fox News
on or something like this or or whatever
I see so many consumer subscription ads
for apps I've never like even heard of
it's crazy actually I wonder in some
cases might a road that perceive trust
you know and over time like it's no
longer like breaking between Walter con
kite you know to sell you Colgate like
feels like it's a little bit more
accessible so I wonder if that that's
going to change the same as uh for
terrestrial radio too I hear so often I
hear
Babel and and n and like so many like
thres radio buys and I mean you probably
know this but like I've heard it's
depending on how you target can be
cheaper than you think especially
probably at your scale you know you're
spending five figures on Facebook a day
it's like probably not that crazy yeah I
think that TV radio are different today
than they were not to make this a a
political thing but during the Trump
trump Administration TV was was at its
height you know it was it was doing
really well yeah whether Fox News or CNN
or MBC everybody's just glued to the
yeah you mean for Effectiveness even I
guess cost probably went up along long
with that too right I think it was the
ratios were good if you had a good brand
which we do so it worked it resonated
well we worked with some of the the
biggest TV buying agencies and they were
blown away by the effectiveness of of
our advertisements that we can actually
get well it's Unique it's like you don't
see an app it's like the ju supposition
of two things like technology and Faith
which I mean exists but it's like
somewhat novel right the combination of
those things so it doesn't surprise me
at least be intriguing compared to your
20th fitness app or like whatever right
it's like something somewhat new so it's
pretty interesting yeah and the
creatives were a little bit different
but they weren't too much I mean we had
James ear jones reads the Bible and so
that helps with creatives but we ran
other ones that didn't didn't have James
Ro Jones that our content team put
together some bangers and so they were
able to perform really well and set us
up for understanding the media mix
models but TV buying radio buying
totally different animal you're making
big bets on Prime times and and these
kind of earlier shows and then you have
to have a a 50% strategy covering 50% of
your spend that's very well spread out
across many channels time slots so that
you can have some consistencies because
a Tuesday prime time one week may just
be the best thing you've ever seen and
may be the worst thing you ever seen the
next week so it's it's very volatile and
you just have to understand that
volatility and bring some some calmness
to that that turbulence yeah I was I was
gonna ask like how does your team divide
your focus between like customer
engagement product development right
like actually on what you build versus
like you know your internal optimization
around pay walls and stuff like that
versus like feels like this whole
Performance Marketing and advertising
and acquisition that's probably like a
whole technology stack right like how do
you like as leadership team or whatever
however you think about you know your
your pie of Cor Focus like how do you
break it down like how much resourcing
and thought goes into the different sort
of categories of work the tech product
is the most Central and we know that
it's extremely important for the you
know I oversee the technology and the
product now and then I work very closely
on the day-to-day for Performance
Marketing and we've hired a a VP of
marketing he ran all of our life cycle
and retention marketing and then now
he's taking over that Performance
Marketing so I'm handing him over the
Reign and he's been doing a great job so
that was like kind of the Performance
Marketing was closely related to the
technical side of the business yeah so
it was just all Under One Roof uh when
we started and so that made it easy
because I had a lot of empathy with the
marketers because I was the marketer and
so I was like Hey Tech Team and I'm
running the TCH I'm like hey guys I'm I
get it I get it it's you know we're
getting another request and it's coming
at you you know and you got to get it
done yesterday so it created a lot of
empathy where I was able to have a
different perspective than probably most
Engineers that I got to feel the pain of
needs from the marketing team where a
lot of times when it's divided and so
really it was one cohesive hole and then
we still operate even though I'm more of
uh of a partner transitioning it over
but it's still built into our DNA so
we're closely aligned on that and so
really it's we don't really divide it up
but we know that there's a priority hey
if the tech product is not working
correctly if not sending the right
signals if it doesn't have the right
flows if something you know we're
watching each step of the flow if
something's broken there the whole thing
collapses vice versa if something on the
on the marketing side if a creative goes
sideways or gets dropped out of the of
the list or or something happens over
there if a change happens in Facebook
platform and or YouTube or whatever and
one of the signals goes down they have
to adjust and then we you know we have
to work in tandem so it's a very unified
front and we don't really divide it up
like a normal organization I feel like
that's one of the biggest things we've
seen talking to larger customers who are
considering migrating to revenue cat
like existing apps that are large and
want to use Revenue cat is there's often
a dysfunction between marketing and
Engineering where the marketing team is
like fighting for resources they're not
tightly integrated and similarly like
often to very successful apps
performance rolled up to like a CTO or
like a very technical or they built it
into as part of the machine this was a
realization sort of mid or mid into of
this journey for me I talked to um I
think it somebody from blinkist actually
and like how they did you know because
they were very successful early on on
this and you know it all ran up to their
CTO right and he was you know he
integrated like all this stuff and made
sure it all ran and then you were saying
Ryan just like elevating the urgency of
those requests to Engineers because like
they don't always understand and and
also I find too on marketing sometimes
marketers will totally hamstrung by
something which to an engineer is
Trivial right it's like oh uh and you
just like if you can connect that and
like clear that barrier like suddenly
you can unlock a lot of value but I
think businesses like yours it's not app
and then layer marketing on it right
like the whole machine is like one big
product right one big business which I
don't know if everybody's figured that
out yet and we talked to uh Jason Van
the mura on the podcast two years ago
now and he was head of growth
engineering and this sounds like that's
that's what you've built and maybe
that's like a big takeaway for a lot of
organizations who have dysfunction
between marketing and Engineering is
like you need to like rethink how these
teams work together because when you
compare growth and Engineering together
to be more effective it's going to be
way more effective do you have the
engineers like dedicated to growth and
Performance Marketing stuff we actually
don't uh we don't have Engineers
dedicated towards it it's more of
everybody's a growth engineer right I
mean at a venture back startup yes David
that's kind of true yeah it's one road
map so we don't have different road maps
that I think that's one of the key
things that I learned is don't have
different road maps make sure that your
product road map is taking into account
the whole organization and making sure
that everyone's getting visibility into
that and understanding the priority and
priority shifts and then modeling out
the ramifications of if we delay this
this is what we can expect and so giving
people more that I'm not the you know I
wouldn't say I'm perfect on this but
that's the ideal state of we do have one
road map it's a living road map it's
constantly changing and it's based on
different stakeholders so that
everyone's aware of what's coming and so
that you know I think that's how we've
solved it rather than saying okay
there's going to be a team dedicated to
this because when you're small and
Scrappy and I still consider us small
and Scrappy we run a lean team is when
there's some Engineers over there that
seem like they have a little bit of
downtime and you you have a hey come
over here you end up in this like
interlocking resource straints
constraints where like one team will
have a little bit of extra resources and
then but there's team with the need
we're at this stage now where we have
like multiple engineering teams and
growing and I think one of the things
that's made it somewhat more successful
is basically us having to go and do
being my CTO and I like repr
prioritizations like and just moving
people around constantly to like because
yeah you lack that visibility and stuff
and but you know I don't think anybody's
got it figured out I love the the one
road mapap thing I don't know I'm trying
to the zero road maps I don't want any
road maps just ask me what's our road
map it's whatever we're working on right
now everything else is just ideas hot
take all right no road
maps there's just today we have to live
in the moment Ryan you know one tiny
little example from what you were just
talking about that I just experienced
like last week in My Little Indie app my
little weather app I've known for like
18 months that our onboarding sucks but
I wanted to focus on the product and so
I kind ignored the onboarding and I like
just put together like what I thought
was like the most simple onboarding that
my cousin who's doing the development
could possibly do and so for like 18
months it's been like eating away at me
like we got to fix the onboarding we got
to fix but I never talked to him about
it and so just last week I finally like
had the conversation like and like laid
out the whole thing of like okay we have
a hard paywall onboarding is everything
and like we need to start running some
Cycles on onboarding here's like the
expectations I see like if we improve
onboarding I think we can improve
conversion by X-ray and I had this whole
like 40 minute conversation and lots of
back and forth and just having that
conversation on that level to like get
on the same team that hey we actually
need to spend some Cycles on this was a
huge unlock for us as like a little
twers team I can't imagine like as a
bigger organization that is facing a lot
of this dysfunction even if you can't
necessarily combine all the teams and
create a growth engineer or whatever
just like break down those communication
barriers between
growth and Engineering so that you're
all on that same team and understand
where those roadblocks are I try to
break down the barriers David just
nobody wants to hear it when they
actually know what I think that's the
problem they don't want to know you
don't want to know what the road map
looks like it's crazy in
there yeah one question would be how do
you think about the product road map and
so we have a SAS portion and a and a
consumer portion you can kind of look at
as a two-sided Marketplace like an Etsy
or something where we connect people and
pastors and I find that in consumer
subscription World in a directed
consumer application the rap can be a
little more fuzzy than a a SAS and so in
the SAS world there's a lot more
modeling there's a lot more math towards
features because you understand like hey
if we roll out this product we can have
a net revenue retention increase because
we can now upsell for this and we think
there's going to be a 3% adoption rate
you can do that a little bit in consumer
but when I've talked to other D Toc
companies I find that that's less
prevalent than in the SAS world so how
do you I guess a question for you how do
you think about it at uh at Revenue cat
about your road map and modeling yeah I
mean I think that really depends on how
you're pricing which is the reason it
doesn't work in consumer as well is
because like some sasses can do really
nice alicart pricing where you're like
okay you want feature X is our core
feature and then you want feature y okay
we'll just add on you know another
charge per seed or whatever to your
contract and so you can very easily go
okay we think 20% of our customers will
use this it's $10,000 a year bang like
that's our value and there it is pretty
nice and also usually that's coupled
with a like pretty understood B2B
Salesforce where you're like I know how
to get these folks to convert to this
and you can incentivize people to do
that too it's like hey sell this new
$10,000 widget add-on and I think you'd
be surprised like I would love to know
at like a sales Salesforce maybe is like
the extreme example but like say mid to
late stage midcap SAS companies I would
bet the majority of their Salesforce is
not like selling Salesforce it's sell
cross whatever right it's all about just
expanding it's has nothing to do now
Revenue C we actually our specific case
is different because of the way we price
it's like mostly based on volume so it's
like a little bit harder because it's
like well we price on volume for
everything else so it's like you add in
a new thing and it just for us it ends
up getting kind of baked out in like how
much pressure we get we can you know in
like a contract negotiation or whatever
if we're adding in features and things
like that but it's a little bit less all
a cart I need a mixed media modeling uh
model for it right I just know if I
build a more useful product like people
will pay for it more pay more for it and
then I just figure that like a little
bit of horse trading we'll find the
right price so I don't benefit from that
modeling so I don't have a road map why
I'm just like well we'll just build
whatever but to that point too like
sometimes you'll have like key customers
that will be like we need X we will
literally sign a contract for y if you
guys build X today and like okay now we
have a road map like this is getting
built right now because it's gonna like
it's a bird in the hand but yeah I just
feel like generally and I think I don't
know if this is true out if this is like
a a B2B thing I think it's kind of true
for all businesses it's kind of actually
I think the the philosophical
underpinnings of of media mix modeling
is just there's so much so many inputs
to these systems and like so many
uncertainties that I think if you try to
overly simplify and be like oh this
lever moves this number and if you like
TR over focus on that stuff I think you
can end up driving to like really odd
conclusions there's probably some
relationship right between lever a and
output B but if you're not considering
everything else I I find this too with
like I think you see this a lot in like
funnel funnel optimization right it's
like okay you move your pay wall from
the beginning to the end like you were
saying yeah you'll change or from the
end to the beginning you'll change your
conversion rate but you're G to it's
going to have other effects right and
which may or may not be localized to
that change which then makes it hard to
manage and and measure so you have to
make sure you're measuring multiple data
points and then I still think there's
like I don't know this might be just
personal I feel like there's still room
for craft right there's still room for
like gut feel and being like me like I
think
this feels better and like we should do
this but as much as I'm I look at
dashboards all day I'm very data driven
but you know I don't know if we don't
have if we don't have some human magic
going into product creation the AIS are
just going to replace us and wouldn't
that be terrible well yeah depends what
magic is you know might we might find
out that uh our magic wasn't as magical
as we thought isn't that magic after
nope nope see as soon as you have a road
map you're replaceable so like uh no
road map can't be replaced by AI how do
you manage the be to road map Ryan I
think a lot of people would be curious
about that at your stage and given all
that we've discussed you mean like
features specifically David or like just
B Toc like because we kind of like did
this chase a rabbit on the B2B side but
most of our listeners are B Toc so I
wanted to kind of bring it back to like
what do you do on the BTC side that
maybe folks listening can learn from
when it comes to the BTC side I really
think of subscription is is kind of your
core for your your monetization but my
general thoughts are post idfa
subscription is not enough I think
dualingo is a perfect case study of
subscription plus ads they also have
some other monetization it's less so but
they do have some other monetization
paths and they have one time so they
have ads subs and then onetime upsell so
they actually multi-time upsells right
like it's consumable like they can you
can buy like yeah non-recurring but like
you can consume many like gem refills or
whatever yeah and so you can start
looking at them with some of the the
lens that's been applied to Consumer
subscriptions lately which is with some
SAS metrics and so I think that I look
at across those three lenses one
subscription is going to be my core ads
is my secondary and then one time
purchases or upsells is another Avenue
in which I have to figure out how can I
monetize across my user base so then I I
generally start with Revenue as my
Northstar since I think that's the best
metric for a company just Revenue same
we agree on that Ryan yeah yeah it's in
the name it's in the name and so I think
that we we start there and we figure out
how can we add value since we have both
sides of the marketplace along those
lines for our consumer so they're going
to give us money what value do they get
in exchange and then how can we make
sure that that money coming to us is
shared with that money in the form of
value is shared with our pastors and our
leaders and so that's how we look at our
BDC application is across those three
Revenue lines Revenue being the
Northstar and then what features can we
add that increase each one of those
subscriptions is kind of tried and true
and there's a lot of tactics around that
ads that's tried and true a lot of
tactics one time is where you have to
get a little bit creative for your space
for us it's a lot different than maybe a
duelingo or something like that my
church used to have the little candles
they charge you a quarter to light so
maybe that could work yeah yeah books
right so all these things yeah yeah one
time content right sorry I've had to
hold back I had a lot of zingers in this
one but I was like try to try to I don't
know where the line is you know what I'm
flexible and flexible I did train to
become a pastor so there's going to be a
lot of judgment if
you I imagine David had a question on
here just like cultur I do imagine you
kind of have to be take it pretty
lightly to like run a tech company in
this space and everybody's got to be
very like open-minded and very chill
about this I like to say that we took a
for the the people that come from a
religious background we took a Solomon
approach to things uh Solomon in the Old
Testament uh built a temple the Temple
of the god right but he got the best got
the best Artisans from around the area
and it didn't matter which religion they
came from it was just the best and they
had to be able to apply their best and
so that's how we we do think about it we
are very much missional and so even if
you don't come from a Christian
background which is the content that's
on our platform you have to be
empathetic towards that space and you
have to be aligned with wanting to
create value so there's very much a
missional component but we don't have
like this strict restriction sales is a
little bit different because you're
interfacing with these religious
organizations so you have to have this
trust in there and generally people are
going to trust when it comes to relig
people of their their same kind but we
don't have any strict things it's more
strict religious we're not a religious
organization we don't have like a
doctrine of faith and so we just look
for people that just want to do good in
the world want to see kind kind of
values communities created and so that's
how we we filter at some point in time I
think maybe it became a misunderstood
that that you should join a company when
you don't believe in the mission because
it's a good mic or whatever right that's
actually a benefit to you because like I
think that mission is so specific and
charged in some way right or just like
very clear and I think asking that very
directly is probably somewhat easy right
in your not easy but nobody's getting to
day one on prey.com being like you do
what you know what I mean every
Everybody kind of understands what
they're getting into and why which is
nice it's nice to have those selectors
those filters that happen naturally
right yep yep that is true no one's
surprised should that be a screening
question do you believe in consumer
subscription apps to pray to the god of
David what do you think my founder
interview is for we probably should put
it earlier in the process right I was
like do you believe we're in the Techno
the techn capital Singularity and you
want to accelerate uh what no okay uh no
doesn't get that weird I do have Ray
kall's book up here his latest one so
you know I'm all in you wouldn't look at
me funny I actually literally don't ask
that but like maybe I should well Ryan
this has been a ton of fun we do need to
wrap up but as we do wrap up was there
anything you want to share we're going
to share links to of course pray.com
it's in the name pray.com you can go
check out the apps see what they're
working on such a good brand that's a I
don't want to ask how much that.com cost
you but it was probably worth it
expensive and fair and we'll link to
your personal LinkedIn which I think is
really cool too the name of you're
LinkedIn as purpose so you must have
been like really early on LinkedIn to be
able to get the title instead of like
your your name so you're like handle on
LinkedIn as purpose we'll share that in
a link to the app as well but anything
else you wanted to share as we're
wrapping up no just thank you for having
me this has been a great conversation
longtime listener and Jacob's blushing
and but this is one of the most valuable
podcasts in the consumer probably the
most in the CSS space so I really
appreciate it thanks for having
me thanks so much for listening if you
have a minute please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player you can
also stop by chat. sub club.com to join
our private community
[Music]